Leo Varghese

Fullstack Developer

Passionate and focused Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in programming. Have a strong desire for knowledge and challenges. Actively involved with the latest technology and updates in the public cloud platforms and web development field.



✓ leogopuran@gmail.com

+91 9745518391

Ernakulam, India

in linkedin.com/in/leovarghese

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

03/2019 - Present

Kerala, India

Tata Consultancy Services Limited is an Indian multinational information technology service and consulting company.

Key Responsibilities

- Working as Fullstack Developer for the client Belgium Post. Belgium Post is responsible for the delivery of national and international mails.
- Migrate existing on-premises client applications to the cloud platforms like AWS, Azure with highly scalable and cost-optimized
- Design, develop and maintain highly available, performanceoptimized & secure applications using microservice architecture.
- Design, develop and maintain automated pipelines for continuous integration and deployment of application resources.

Senior Software Engineer **IBS Software Services**

09/2016 - 02/2019

Kerala, India

IBS is a leading global provider of new generation IT solutions to the Travel, Transportation and Logistics industries.

Kev Responsibilities

- Worked as Fullstack Developer for the customer Expedia Group. Expedia Group is an American global travel technology company.
- Developed and maintained microservices and web tools to help in driving the business for airline bookings across large number of Expedia point of sales.
- To communicate with the major travel fare aggregators to collect airline details and live fares to make available for the Expedia
- Troubleshoot and provide support during issues.

CERTIFICATES

AWS CERTIFIED SOLUTION ARCHITECT-ASSOCIATE (10/2019 - 10/2022)

Validation Number: RDFL01G1MFE11QKC

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (2020 -Present)

Indira Gandhi National Open University

Bachelor of Technology (2012 - 2016)

Adi Shankara Institute of Engineering and Technology, Kerala, India

Computer Science Engineering

• CGPA - 7.94

High School (2010 - 2012)

Little Flower Public School, Muringoor, Kerala, India

Computer Science stream

• 81.2%

SOFT SKILLS

Quality of Work

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CS Fundamentals

Data Structure, Object Oriented Programming, Operating Systems, Databases, Coding Standards

Tech Stack

Java, Spring Boot, Angular 11, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript, Amazon Web Services, Azure, Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Maven, Git, Perforce, SVN, Bash

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Vanishing Wall

Platform for people to post anonymous feeds that vanishes after a certain duration and gets replaced by new feeds. The application runs using the WebSocket protocol.

Green Mart

An innovative project where people living in the same locality can sell and buy organic farm products at their wished price.

Online Exam portal

A freelance project built for Path Solutions India Pvt Ltd.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Selected as the 1 team among the top 21 teams for STARTUP BOX young entrepreneurs programme organized by the Kerala Start Up Mission(KSUM) (06/2015 – 12/2015)

Kerala Start Up Mission(KSUM)

Won Team Champ award and customer appreciation for designing and implementing a web platform that can automate developer tasks.

IBS Software Services

Customer recognition and spot awards for excellence in deliverables.

Tata Consultancy Services

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English (WRS) Full Professional Proficiency Malayalam (WRS)

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Coding

Innovate

Technology

Travel

Football